

Matthew Yu

Assistant Customer Digital Experience Development Manager (Product Owner)

yuwanghin97874371@gmail.com

65910076

Tseung Kwun O, Hong Kong

05 July, 1990 🧰

bit.ly/3btTzP8 📆

Master's degree in ITM from HKBU and am currently working as an Assistant Customer Digital Experience Development Manager (Product Owner) at The Hong Kong Jockey Club. Managing a product with over 100,000 Unique Visitor per racing cycle and I am responsible for maintaining and prioritizing the product roadmap, delivering user-centered digital application across the Club's range of digital channels, including the mobile app, website, and cross-media platforms.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Customer Digital Experience Manager (Product Owner) The Hong Kong Jockey Club

12/2021 - Present

Hong Kong

Achievements/Tasks

- Maintain and prioritize the product road map, deliver user-centered digital application projects across the Club's range of digital channels, including the mobile app, website and cross-media platforms.
- Transform business analysis, customer feedback and market research outcomes in to digital business insights and product requirement.
- Translate product roadmap features into well-defined product requirements including Epic, features, user stories, and acceptance criteria.
- Be part of the scrum team, work closely with development team to maximize value of sprint deliveries
- Familiar with Agile, Scrum and tools such as Jira, Confluence and Slack
- Work with UI designer for the user interface to support user acceptance test and product launch activities
- Managing a product with over 100,000 Unique Visitor per racing cycle
- Managed Project
- Racing Touch is a One-Stop interactive racing app which brings together comprehensive racing information, live streaming and instant betting. The graphically-rich interface together with quality 3D horses and the use of gamification offer an innovative betting experience
- Download Link: https://m.hkjc.com/en/betting-appsand-website.html#racing-touch

EXPERTISE

Agile Scrum Master

Agile Methodology (Scrum, Kaban)

Prince2 Project Management

JIRA, Trello, Slack

Performance, Functional & System Testing, UAT

Leadership Sprint Planning

Change Management SEO

Google Analytics Vendor Management

Data Analytics Big Data

LANGUAGES

Cantonese • • • • (

English • • • • •

Mandarin Chinese

CERTIFICATES

PRINCE2 - Project Management Foundation (2018)

PRINCE₂

GAQM - Certificated of Scrum Master (CSM) (2017)

GAOM

Open Water Diver (2020)

NAUI Worldwide

SSI - 國際唎酒師 (2021)

Sake Service Institute

WSET Level 2 Award in Wines -Pass With Merit (2021)

Wine & Spirit Education Trust

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Project Manager The Hong Kong Jockey Club

08/2021 - 11/2021

Hong Kong

Achievements/Tasks

- Manages projects or phases of projects covering part or all the full development lifecycle
- Implementation support or other specialist functions (e.g., Release Management, Testing)
- Directly accountable for project resources and for identifying project stakeholders at an early stage and manages them effectively through appropriate matrix management; plans, organises and controls projects in order to deliver required quality business solutions within agreed timescales and budget
- Defines the scope of the project, manages project objectives, risks, issues and resources
- Ensures project deliverables are capable of achieving the benefits defined in the project proposal.
- Manages project
- Racing Touch is a One-Stop interactive racing app which brings together comprehensive racing information, live streaming and instant betting. The graphically-rich interface together with quality 3D horses and the use of gamification offer an innovative betting experience
- Download Link: https://m.hkjc.com/en/betting-appsand-website.html#racing-touch

Product Manager

ZeroToSix - Asiaray Media Group Limited

11/2019 - 08/2021

Hong Kong

Achievements/Tasks

- Certification of PRINCE 2 & Agile Scrum Master. Indepth knowledge of JIRA & Confluence Agile tools
- Analyze technical requirements from clients, internal stakeholders, and development risks with IT team, define new features /enhancement/tasks and obtain management buy-in.
- Collaborate with business users and IT to provide technical direction to create product prototypes, UIUX, user flow diagrams, storyboards on systems analysis, design, development, testing, and deployment.
- Define project scope & timelines, people resources/work taskforce, budget, communication, and delivery of the solution into production.
- Provide monthly reports to top management for projects on deliverables, impacts/challenges, and measurable. Responsible for vendor management and work with external third parties.
- Agile Practice Arrange Sprint Planning, Story card estimation, Daily standup allows members of the development team to share status updates and identify obstacles and Retrospective session
- Graduated with a Master of Information Technology Management with a technical background. Good experience in Web, Mobile development, Data analytics, and Cloud technical knowledge (Kubernetes, Docker, DevOps, CI/CD, Microservices)

AVAILABILITY

1 Month

WORK EXPERIENCE

Digital Project Manager TBWA HK Omnicom Group

11/2017 - 11/2019

Hong Kong

Achievements/Tasks

- Certificated of Prince2 Project Management. Manage project schedules, set and meet project development budgets
- Develop user flows, wireframes and scope out digital project based on creative concepts
- Manage a team of designers, developers, external vendors through all stages of a project from concept, prototyping, production, QA to deployment
- Communicate with stakeholder to gather business requirement and ensure stakeholder expectations are met throughout the project lifecycle
- Consult on the capabilities and limitations of various web, mobile best practice design principles and usability
- Familiar with Google Analytics, SEO and Adobe Omniture to monitor A/B Test Result

Software Quality Assurance Analyst JobsDB Hong Kong Limited

06/2014 - 11/2017

Hong Kong

Achievements/Tasks

- Experience in gathering user requirement, managing project scope, timeline, and budgets on JIRA & Confluence for setting up a regional QA Environment
- Arrange weekly catch up with Customer Service Team to identify business users needs
- Certificated of Agile Scrum Master and facilitate between UX Designer, Engineer and Product Owner to create user stories, project prioritization and define business objective
- Develop Test Plan, User Acceptance Plan and Test Summary Report - Perform User Acceptance Testing (UAT) and System Integration Test in Agile Development Cycle
- Achievements: Personalisation Job Recommendation

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Information Technology Management Hong Kong Baptist University

2018 - 2020

Bachelor of Science with Honours in Web Technologies

Open University of HK

2012 - 2014

Higher Diploma in Computer and Information Engineering
Hong Kong Institute of Vocational Education

2008 - 2012

J Percy Page High School Alberta Canada

2007 - 2008